Sasori...
（チヨ）サソリ…
（マイト･ガイ）よーし 休憩終了！
All right, break's over.
Guy Sensei, are you sure?
（ロック･リー）
ガイ先生 もういいんですか？
（ガイ）ああ もうバッチリだ
Yeah. I'm totally fine.
I woke up completely refreshed.
ズガーンと爽やかな目覚めだ
Neji.
（パックン）ネジ
No problem. He has appalling
recuperative power.
（日向ひゅうがネジ）問題ない
あきれるほどの回復力だ
（パックン）うん あとは…
Uh-huh... So that leaves...
（テンテン）私のほうも大丈夫
I'm ready to go, too.
（ガイ）よおし
All right, now to make up
for the time we lost resting,
休憩の遅れを取り戻すために
これまでの２倍のペースで行くぞ
we're going to double the pace.
（テンテン）ええ～！
What?!
（リー）いえ ３倍で行きましょう
No, let's make it triple.
そうすれば
最初の予定より早く着きます
If we do that, we'll arrive
earlier than first planned.
なるほど
I see.
よし みんな
せっかくだから４倍で行くぞ
All right guys,
let's make it quadruple
the pace while we're at it.
おお どうした？
What's the matter?
That's impossible,
no matter how you consider things.
（ネジ）どう考えたって無理だ
（テンテン）だから
そのノリやめてくださいってば
I told you guys to stop
getting so carried away!
（リー）ガイ先生 だから
３倍って言ったじゃありませんか
Guy Sensei, that's why
I said triple the pace.
（パックン）リー
それもちょっと違うぞ
Lee, that's a little off, too.
（はたけカカシ）さて
Now then...
That should be enough rest...
もういいだろう
休憩はこの辺にして
そろそろ行きましょう
Break time is over.
We should get going.
（チヨ）うん
（カカシ）２人とも起きろ
Wake up, you two.
We're leaving.
さっ 出発だ
O-Okay.
（春野はるのサクラ）は… はい
（うずまきナルト）ん んん…
（ナルト）もうちょっと
A little longer...
Let me sleep a little longer.
もうちょっとだってばよ
（カカシ）我愛羅君を
助けに行くんだろ
You're going to save Gaara, aren't you?
（ナルト）はっ
もちろんだってばよ
Of course I am!
♪～
～♪
The Death of Gaara!
（テマリ）敵のアジトがあるのは
確かこの方角
The enemy hideout
should be in this direction...
I'm sorry... Gaara...
（テマリ）すまん… 我愛羅
We'll now be entering
the final stage.
（暁のリーダー）
これより最終段階に入る
（干柿ほしがき鬼鮫きさめ）
煩わしいハエどもはどうします？
What shall we do about the pesky flies?
（ゼツ）これは予想以上の速度だ
They're moving
at a greater speed than anticipated.
（暁のリーダー）問題ない
足止めの効果は出ている
No problem.
We stalled them effectively.
Just ignore them.
物資 それに保険もかけてある
Besides, we've got some insurance.
In the end, we'll be the ones
who have to take care of them.
（デイダラ）
結局 後始末することになるのは
俺たちだけどな うん
Let's hurry and finish
things up here, Deidara.
（サソリ）とっとと終わらせるぞ
デイダラ
We've got guests to greet.
俺たちが客を
出迎えなきゃならねえんだ
You'll want to catch
a breath before that, don't you?
その前に 一息つきてえだろ
That's right.
そうだったな
We have welcoming preparations
to take care of.
歓迎の準備が必要だった うん
Man, they're sure a pain.
（鬼鮫）やれやれ
めんどくさいですね
（飛段ひだん）フッ 俺たちは人柱力が
なかなか見つからねえってのに
And we're having a hard time
finding our Jinchuriki...
（角都かくず）そうイライラするな
Don't get so irritated.
We just need to take care
of our own missions.
俺たちは自分のノルマを
見つければいい
That's enough idle chatter.
（暁のリーダー）
ムダ話はそこまでだ 集中しろ
Concentrate! Mistakes will
not be tolerated from here on.
これから先は
毛先ほどのミスも許されん
Each team will be deployed
as I just announced.
（バキ）各班の配置は
今 言ったとおりだ
The absence of Lord Kazekage
is a highly classified matter!
（バキ）風影様の不在は
超一級の極秘事項
だが すでに情報は漏れていると
考えて行動するんだ
However, operate under
the assumption
that the information has
already been leaked.
It's conceivable that the nearby lands
この混乱に乗じ
近隣諸国が攻め入ってくることが
十分に考えられる
will take advantage of this confusion
and execute an attack.
Don't think of this as
just an ordinary border patrol.
ただの国境警備だと思うな
The teams that are ready
will depart at once.
準備ができた班から
直ちに出発せよ！
どうした？ マツリ
What's the matter, Matsuri?
Is this really okay?
（マツリ）本当に
これでいいんですか？
Is what okay?
何がだ？
Lord Gaara has been kidnapped.
我愛羅様がさらわれたんですよ
And yet, here we are guarding
a border
なのに助け出そうともせずに
来るか来ないか分からぬ敵を
恐れて国境を警備
for an enemy who may or may not come
instead of trying to save him.
It's an order from our superiors.
We can only obey.
上からの命令だ 従うしかあるまい
（マツリ）そんな…
No way!
我愛羅様は砂隠すなかくれの…
私たちの風影なんですよ
Lord Gaara is the Hidden Sand's...
our Kazekage!
そんなことは分かってる
我愛羅は私の弟だ
I know that!
Gaara's my little brother, you know!
あっ…
I'm sorry...
すみません
This way.
（パックン）こっちだ
Right!
（ガイ）おう
I don't like it.
気に入らないなあ
What is it, Neji?
どうしたんです？ ネジ
Is it an enemy?
敵？
いや その逆だ
No, just the opposite.
I don't feel any enemy presence at all.
That's what's bothering me.
敵の気配がまるで感じられない
そこが引っかかる
えっ
Here they went so far as to use...
あれほどの術を使ってまで
that powerful of a Jutsu
in an attempt to stall us.
俺たちを足止めしようと
していたのに
Then...
それじゃあ…
Could it be...?
もしかして…
They no longer need to stall us.
（カカシ）足止めの必要が
なくなったということか
I'm saying there's
a good chance of that.
その可能性もあるということじゃ
（サクラ）まさか…
Don't tell me...
（チヨ）こ… こヤツ
H-He's...
Hang on, Gaara.
待ってろよ 我愛羅
Naruto, wait up!
（サクラ）ナルト 待って！
Geez.
もう…
Why's that kid trying so hard to
save Gaara who's from a different village?
（チヨ）なぜ あのガキは
ほかの里の我愛羅を
あそこまで助けようとする？
And what in the world is he?
それに あヤツは 一体…
He's also a Jinchuriki.
（カカシ）あいつも人柱力です
ん？
He has the Nine-Tail sealed within him.
（カカシ）それも九尾を封印された
Indeed, Naruto probably
doesn't have much attachment
確かにナルトにとって
砂隠れ自体には
大した思い入れはないでしょう
to the Hidden Sand itself.
しかし 我愛羅君は
あいつと同じ人柱力です
But Gaara is a Jinchuriki Host
just like he is.
More than anyone
in the Hidden Sand,
砂隠れの誰よりもナルトは
彼の気持ちが分かってしまう
Naruto knows how Gaara feels.
After all, the Jinchuriki has been
treated the same way in every village.
人柱力が
どんな扱いを受けてきたか
それはどの里においても
大差ありませんからね
That's exactly why he feels
like he has to save Gaara.
だからこそ 助けずには
いられないんですよ
It doesn't make
any difference to him
木こノ葉はだとか砂だとか
あいつにとっては
if he's from the Leaf or the Sand.
そんなことは
どうでもいいことなんでしょう
For Naruto, Gaara is a friend
ナルトにとって我愛羅君は
同じ痛みを知る仲間なんです
who knows the same pain as he does.
Naruto's dream is to
become the Hokage.
ナルトの夢は
火影ほかげになることなんですが
He was frustrated when he heard
that Gaara had become the Kazekage.
彼が風影になったと聞いて
悔しがっていました
（ナルト）そうか
I see. So Gaara became
the Kazekage, huh?
我愛羅 風影になったのか
But at the same time,
（カカシ）ですが その反面
he was also very happy for
Gaara from the bottom of his heart.
それを心から喜び
祝福していたのもナルトなんです
俺も負けてらんねえってばよ
I won't be outdone by him!
I'll become the Hokage,
no matter what.
ぜってえ火影になってやる
Just you wait, Gaara!
見てろよ 我愛羅！
Naruto has a mysterious power.
（カカシ）ナルトには
不思議な力があるんですよ
However small the words he exchanges,
he makes friends immediately...
あいつは交わす言葉は少なくても
誰とでも
すぐ友達になってしまうんです
with everyone he meets.
I myself have lived a long life.
わしも長生きした
I've seen many things.
数多くの物事を見てきた
And in my own way,
世の道理もそれなりに学んできた
I've learned the nature
of things in this world.
Learning that the alliance with
other lands were for show only,
そして他国との同盟が
形だけのものと分かってしたことが
what I did was to create resources
to protect the Hidden Sand.
我が砂隠れを守るための
算段をつけることじゃった
I'm the one who used the Jutsu...
我愛羅に術を使って
守鶴しゅかくを憑依させたのは
and forced the possession
of the Shukaku on Gaara.
この わしじゃ
After consulting with his father
the Fourth Kazekage, that is.
あヤツの父の
４代目風影と相談してな
What I did to protect the village
ended up just hurting it.
里を守るためにしてきたことが
結果 里を苦しめることになり
そして同盟を信じず
避けてきたほかの里によって
And now a village I avoided
because I couldn't believe in alliances
今 助けられようとしておる
is trying to help us.
Everything I've done might
have been mistaken.
わしのしてきたことは
間違いばかりだったのかもしれん
And now I've gotten old
and learn to give up easily.
そのうえ老いぼれて
諦め癖までついた
Kakashi...
カカシよ
Young people have
so much potential within...
若いとは なんという可能性を
秘めておるものか
I'm so envious.
羨ましいのう
（カカシ）いえいえ
まだ これからですよ
Oh no, you're just getting started...
You're still very much young.
十分 お若いですし
エへ エへ エへへへ…
That's right...
そうじゃな
老いぼれのわしにも...
There might still be something
an old bag like me can do.
まだできることが
あるかもしれんのう
Something I can do.
（チヨ）まだできることが…
It's about finished.
（暁のリーダー）そろそろ仕上げだ
Whose...hand is this?
（我愛羅）誰だ？ この手…
Oh...it's my hand.
なんだ 俺の手か
Have I...become an existence
someone needs?
俺は誰かに必要とされる存在に
なれたのだろうか？
Huh? What?
あれ… なんだ？
Is that me?
俺？
That's me... The me who wanted
to be needed by...someone...
あれが俺…
誰かに必要とされたがってた 俺
Why...? Why did I want
to be like that?
どうして？
なんで
そうなりたかったんだろう？
Why...am I...
an existence that desires that?
俺はなんで
それを望む存在なんだろう？
Those eyes. That nose.
That mouth.
あの目 あの鼻 あの口…
Why?
なぜ…
Why is that Gaara?
なぜ あれが我愛羅
I was inside that...
俺はその中にいた
No...
いや… そもそも俺とはなんだ？
What am I in the first place?
I'm just aware that I'm me.
俺と自覚してるだけで
そもそも何者なんだ？
What am I...in the first place?
I'm just a small...feeling.
ただの小さな感覚…
It's finished.
（暁のリーダー）終わったな
Oh man.
（サソリ）やれやれ
結局 三日三晩
かかっちまったな うん
In the end, it took three days
and three nights.
（鬼鮫）毎度のことながら
しんどいですね
It's exhausting every time, isn't it?
（飛段）ああ 肩が凝っちまったぜ
Ohhh, my shoulders are all stiff.
Good work, everyone.
（暁のリーダー）
みんな ご苦労だった
（カンクロウ）ウッ
I've got a bad feeling
about this.
（カンクロウ）嫌な予感がする
クソッ 何か俺に
できることはないのかよ
Damn it! Isn't there something I can do?
This is the place, huh?
ここか
Gaara is on the other side
of this boulder.
我愛羅はこの岩の中だ
（ガイ）どうやら
結界が張られているな
It looks like they put up a barrier.
What's the plan?
（テンテン）どうします？
（リー）突入しましょう
Let's bust through!
いや
No!
（物音）
（リー）わっ
You're late... Kakashi.
遅かったな カカシ
（カカシ）いやいや
Well, you see...
We got caught up in
something troublesome along the way.
途中 めんどくさいのに
からまれちゃって
ナルト君 サクラさん
Naruto! Sakura!
Kakashi...
（チヨ）カカシよ
By troublesome, you certainly
don't mean me, do you?
めんどくさいのとは
わしのことでは あるまいなあ
Hey!
押忍！
Naruto...
ナルト…
（サクラ）みなさん
一足早かったんですね
We were just a step behind
you guys, huh?
Who's the old woman there?
（テンテン）そっちのおばあさんは？
ああ こちらは
砂の相談役のチヨ様です
Oh, this is Lady Chiyo,
a consultant to the Sand.
Nice to meet you.
よろしくな
さあて やるか？ カカシ
Now, shall we do this, Kakashi?
Yeah.
（カカシ）ああ
Hang on, Gaara.
（ナルト）我愛羅 待ってろよ
♪～
～♪
解説しよう
Allow me to explain!
次回のサブタイトル
ボタンフックエントリーとは
The title of the next episode is,
"Button Hook Entry."
入り口を挟んで左右に展開する
忍者たちの突入方法の１つだ
This refers to a method Ninja
used to break through entrances
by fanning out left and right
with the entrance in between.
ちなみに私の
ダイナミックエントリーを
By the way, it seems
a lot of people tend to confuse
術の名前と勘違いしてる人が
多いようだが
my "Dynamic Entry" as
a name for a Jutsu,
立派な突入方法の１つ
but it's a credited way
to break into places.
スピードは命で
のどもかれる優れものだ
It's an excellent tactic
where speed is of the essence,
and also serves as
an effective diversion!
どうだ！ これで君たちは
How about that?!
N
また１つ 我々の任務について
詳しくなったわけだ
ウハハハハ！
次回
「突入！ ボタン
フックエントリー」
（カカシ）木ノ葉 流行通信
（カカシ）やあ 諸君
きょうは忍の必須アイテムを
紹介するぞ
まず はじめに
木ノ葉の額当てだ
これは 一人前の忍と
認められた証し
防具としてはもちろん
ファッションとしても
注目のアイテムだ
額に巻くのが 一般的だが
装着方法は人それぞれ
個性の見せどころだぞ～
（カカシ）
お次は手裏剣アンド
クナイセット
あらゆる戦闘に活用できる実用品
付属のホルスターを
使えば
持ち運びも
とっても便利
（カカシ）
最後は俺も着てる
木ノ葉ベストだ
戦闘中に手が離せない
なんてときもひと安心
このベストなら
片手で巻物が取り出せるんだ
（ガイ）さらに今ならなんと…
通気性 保湿性に優れた
この究極スーツがついてくるぞ～！
（カカシ）いやあ それ
誰も欲しがらないっしょ
うわあ なんでえ～！
（カカシ）
そんじゃあ またね